A Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Coles Langhorne, 1975-1986
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Elizabeth Coles Langhorne, 1975-1986
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7942-e
This collection consists of 43 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift on 1991 October 7.
Scope and Content Information
With these are related items including a Hemings family genealogy tracing descendants of Betty Hemings; several versions of an article "The Black Family at Monticello"; copies of other articles with pertinent information; and other Jefferson related writings by Langhorne including a grant proposal for a biography of Martha Jefferson Randolph.
Contents List
- "Black Family at Monticello," and related, 1975, n.d., 21 items (Box 1)
- Jefferson-related writings by Elizabeth Langhorne, and related, including grant proposal for a biography of Martha Jefferson Randolph, 1978-1979, n.d., 10 items (Box 1)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, rough draft n.d., AMs (Box 1)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, setting copy with instructions to the printer 1986, 3 folders. TMs (Box 1)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, uncorrected 1986, 2 folders. Galley Proof (Box 1)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, with minor autograph revisions by author, explained in her letter 1986 Oct, 2 folders. Galley Proof (Box 2)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, with autograph revisions initiated by author, editor, and printer error 1986 Dec, Galley Proof. 2 folders (Box 2)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, master set, with instructions to the printer 1986, Page Proof (Box 2)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, with three autograph revisions by author 1986, Page Proof (Box 2)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, used by Melody Ivins to compile index [1986 Dec], Page Proof (Box 3)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, pages from 1st, 2nd, 3rd revisions, with autograph revisions 1986-1987, Page Proof (Box 3)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, miscellaneous pages n.d., TMs (incomplete) (Box 3)
- Monticello: A Family Story by Elizabeth Langhorne, correspondence and front matte 1987, 2 items (Box 3)